Nishant Dougall

M: 0412 202 666 | E: nishantdougall@gmail.com

Profile

I am a Diploma of Community Services graduate with a background in project management. I have eight years of experience working across all stages of the project management lifecycle.

I have completed two tertiary qualifications as an international student and have a unique understanding of the issues and the challenges faced by migrants due to cultural, linguistic, and financial barriers when attempting to navigate our mental health service system.

I am a classic Capricorn - hardworking, rational, and an excellent problem-solver. I am a person of colour, queer, neuro-diverse, gender diverse, and I have lived with psychosocial disability via significant mental health conditions. My lived experience enables me to rapidly build trust and rapport with a broad range of people from various backgrounds and experiences.

I have stepped away from the corporate world because I am passionate about social justice and mental health. Everyone in our community deserves to be mentally healthy and engaged in the community.

Key Skills

- Interpersonal skills I can work effectively and interact comfortably and confidently with people from diverse cultural backgrounds.
- I deeply understand the project management lifecycle and demonstrated the ability to track progress and report against agreed work tasks and milestones.
- Proven ability to effectively collate, analyse and interpret data and information from different sources, design and implement solutions accordingly.
- Deep understanding of issues facing migrants in accessing services regarding mental health and familiarity with barriers to accessing support
- Ability to self-motivate and work independently and collaboratively as a productive team member.
- I possess excellent computer skills and am proficient in word processing, spreadsheets, and database applications.

Volunteer Experience

Community Support Worker

Nov 2022 - Present

Diamond Valley Community Support, Greensborough, VIC

- I am providing emergency aid and advocacy services to individuals in crisis.
- I deliver friendly, non-judgmental, empathetic, and compassionate support while prioritizing client privacy and dignity.
- I assess and evaluate clients' needs and develop an appropriate support response and internal and external referral pathways when appropriate.
- To date, I have conducted over 400 interviews.

Rainbow Connection COVID19 Volunteer

May 2020 - Dec 2020

Thorne Harbour Health, South Yarra, VIC

- The purpose of this service was to give clients of Thorne Harbour Health maintaining meaningful connection to community can have a profoundly positive impact on people's sense of self, feelings of anxiety/distress and wellbeing
- I delivered food support and an opportunity to maintain a meaningful connection to community to socially isolated and immunocompromised LGBTIQ+

•

- I effectively managed client visits, phoning them in advance to confirm delivery arrangements.
- Our team delivered over 2000 packages to Positive Living Centre clients during the pandemic.

maintaining meaningful connections to community has a profoundly positive impact on people's sense of self, feelings of anxiety/distress and general wellbeing. For this reason, and to address the challenges caused by the physical distancing measures in place, Rainbow Connection actively links isolated LGBTI people with the services and supports they need to get by during this time."

Sex On Premise Venue (SOPV) Outreach Worker

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

Thorne Harbour Health, Melbourne, VIC

• I supported clients at SOPVs, allowing them to ask questions about sexual health, HIV, & other health topics & find connections to relevant health services.

Work Experience

Senior Business Analyst

Jan 2016 - Mar 2018

Coutts & Co, London, VIC

- Lead Analyst on regulatory compliance project.
- I successfully established effective collaborations with stakeholders and external organizations.

Business Analyst

Jan 2014 - Dec 2015

Independent Television News (ITN), London, VIC

- I was the lead analyst on a tech project in ITN's Finance dept and was responsible for creating and managing staff training & project comms.
- I supported the Project Manager to successfully implement a new accounting software package.

Project Analyst

Dec 2010 - Dec 2013

National Australia Bank (NAB), Melbourne, VIC

- I identified and documented requirements for a new centralised process on a significant transformational change program.
- I was responsible for designing the solution, drafting the appropriate documents and record keeping as per NAB's policies and procedures regarding project delivery.

Business Banker – Graduate Program

Jan 2009 - Nov 2010

National Australia Bank (NAB), Melbourne, VIC

• I supported my manager in looking after a portfolio of 100 small business clients in the Carlton, most with approximately \$ 2 million in borrowings.

Education		
Diploma of Community Services Master of Finance Bachelor of Business (Marketing)	Melbourne Polytechnic Monash University Queensland University of Tech	2024 2008 2005
Licences & Certifications		
Working With Children Check First Aid Mental Health First Aid SMART Recovery Facilitator Victorian Driver's Licence	Victorian State Government St John Ambulance Australia Mental Health First Aid Australia SMART Recovery Australia VicRoads	2023 2023 2021 2018 2006